## ROBERT MEZIAN

## IT SUPPORT ENGINEER | PROJECT MANAGER

## CONTACT

Granada Hills, CA (818) 517 –1463

robert mezian@outlook.com

Website:

https://www.robertmezian.com

## PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

A proficient, dynamic, top-performing and goal-oriented IT specialist and a project manager with over 4+ years of experience in the relevant field including information technology, legal assisting and technical project management. Experienced and knowledgeable professional seeking to contribute training and acquired skills in a group setting providing all facets of computer support such as installations, troubleshooting as well as maintenance. Committed to driving business success by implementing improved technology, increasing security measures, effectively training teams, and utilizing cost engineering to reduce project expenses.

## EDUCATION

#### **MASTER OF SCIENCE**

Computer Science

Cal State University Northridge August 2023 - present

### **BACHELOR OF ARTS**

**English Literature** 

San Francisco State University

May 2017

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front-end development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
- Back-end development
- Management Information Systems (MIS)
- Website Development
- HTML/JavaScript
- Web frameworks (Django for Python, Spring for Java)
- Scripting languages (e.g., Bash, Shell)

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## IT SUPPORT ENGINEER II // Amazon Web Services, Los Angeles. CA

May 2022 - January 2023

- Diagnose and troubleshoot end user computing problems including analyzing the problem, identification of appropriate resources, testing of proposed fixes and follow-up to ensure the problem has been resolved.
- Create and submit detailed call logs documenting customer interactions that are accurate, thorough, and timely.
- Reviewed and filed pleadings, petitions, and other documents, while training new clerks in legal clerk procedures.
- Inform customer of needed repairs and answers basic questions. Ensures that customer understands and is satisfied with work completed.
- Follow all standard operating procedures (SOP) through the effective use of Knowledge management.
- Create and implement long-term technical solutions for repetitive or serious support problems. Determine the right solution, working with stakeholders, partner teams, and peers. Deliver independently, with minimal guidance.

### IT SPECIALIST // Ortho Engineering Inc., Granada Hills, CA

May 2019 - May 2022

- Successfully monitoring security certificated and company compliance measures, while offering quality and authentic technical support to the company staff.
- Compiled an inventory hardware list of all sites, totaling all the necessary information for audit and traceability purpose.
- Installation and updating company software and hardware, while troubleshooting computer problems.
- Efficiently installed, configured, and routinely upgraded software and hardware for end-users, while anticipating and reporting cost of replacing or updating computer systems.
- Presenting project statuses to mid-managers and senior leaders every week to assist completing task.
- Assisting customers with analyzing and resolving hardware and software issues that allowed the continuation of an efficient work environment.
- Scheduling weekly meeting to discuss the new or unsolved issues with the team and came up with possible solutions to prevent same issues happen again.

# CORE COMPETENCIES

- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.
- · Communication skills.
- · Organized and time-management.
- · Interaction between departments.
- · Analytical abilities.
- · Creativity and innovation.
- · Problem solving.
- · Resourcefulness.
- · Perseverance.
- Technical Writing
- CRM Management
- Project Management
- IT Compliance
- · Counseling and Advising
- Training and Mentoring.
- Strategy Development.
- · Administration and Dependability.
- Data-Driven Practices.
- · Conflict Management

## **EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

### FRONT DESK CLERK // Boucher LLP, Woodland Hills, CA

Aug 2018 – May 2019

- Maintaining electric files and archives evidence files upon final disposition, while responding to internal and external discovery requests.
- Occasionally organized exhibits for large legal motions, while developing a fully functional and strong distribution system.
- Collaborating with clients to obtain legal documents as needed to expedite cases, also responsible for copying, redacting, and converting video and audio files as requested in compliance of state of law and court orders.
- Prepared affidavits of documents and maintained document filed and case correspondence.
- Reviewed and filed pleadings, petitions, and other documents, while training new clerks in legal clerk procedures.
- Drafted business and nonprofit formation transactional documents, as well as prepared briefs and legal memoranda regarding statement of issues involved.
- Operated personal computers, word processors, duplicating machines, audio-recording devices and other office machines.

#### ASSISTANT DIRECTOR // CA, Legal Resource Center, SFSU

June 2016 - Aug 2017

- Administering a \$50,000 yearly budget while allocating funds of events, speakers and center necessities.
- Managed and performed administrative tasks, including bookkeeping using Excel and QuickBooks.
- Coordinated small and large events networking with organizations in the Bay Area, while managing the legal referral center composing of employees and interns.
- Managed staff performance and led evaluations yearly and as necessary, while organizing company initiatives and making proper arrangements to meet department objectives.
- Managed vendor relationships and all vendor event contracts, while developing event production schedules and timelines.